我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist.
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
But secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
但当我女儿从未来时空前来帮忙
But when my daughter came back from the future to help,
她改变了现在
she changed the present.
现在我们的世界比以往更加危险
And now our world is more dangerous than ever,
我是唯一一个来得及拯救世界的人
and I'm the only one fast enough to save it.
我是闪电侠
I am the Flash.
地球九十
你失败了
You failed.
你为什么要这样做
Why are you doing this?
这是你自作自受
You did this to yourself.
而今天  所有人都将毁灭
And now all of you will perish.
地球一
我叫约翰·迪根  和在座的大多数人一样
My name is Dr. John Deegan, and I, like most of you,
是一名精神病学家
I'm a psychiatrist.
你们知道我的病人最常跟我说什么吗
Do you know what my patients tell me the most?
他们感到自卑
They feel inferior.
我想说的是  无论我们承认与否
I'm here to tell you, whether we admit it or not,
有些人  他们就是生来幸运
some people, they're just born lucky,
由此引出真正的问题  不完美
which leads us to the real problem, imperfection.
我们怎能期望会成为
How can we ever hope to feel like
超人或女超人
supermen or superwomen
如果我们不能首先实现超我本身
without first becoming super ourselves?
我来告诉各位怎么做
I'm here to tell you how, folks.
如果我们采用优生学的认知  我觉得
If we utilize eugenic insights, I feel--
科学怪人  回到你那疯狂的实验室吧
Hey, Frankenstein, go back to your mad scientist lab.
女士  请等一下  好吗
Ma'am, ma'am, please-- would you wait, please?
各位  请听一听
Folks, folks, folks, please listen.
我只是想说  我们能真正帮助到病人
I'm just saying, we can truly help our patients.
听我一言
Listen to me!
[美国精神病学协会]
这帮白痴
Idiots!
博士
Doctor.
约翰·迪根博士
Dr. John Deegan.
我需要你的帮助  约翰
I need your help, John.
去别人那里搞恶作剧吧  蠢货
Go find someone else to prank, douchebag.
老天  你是什么人
My God, what are you?
超出你理解范围的存在
Something beyond your comprehension.
我长途跋涉来到此时此地
I've traveled far to this place and time
将此重担托付于你
to lay this precious burden at your feet.
使用此书按照你的意愿来重塑世界
Use this book to reshape the world as you see fit.
让他们看看一个真正的神能做什么  约翰
Show them what a real god can do, John.
为什么是我
Why me?
你有远见
You have vision.
那本书是你脱胎换骨的关键  约翰
That book holds the key to your transformation, John,
你只需要打开它
and all you have to do is open it.
善用它  约翰
Use it wisely, John.
宇宙尽在你的手中
The universe is in your hands.
我能看见
I can--I can see...
我能看见一切
I can see everything.
给你一句忠告
And a word of advice:
放开去想
think big.
闪 电 侠
第五季
第九集
《异世界》
亲爱的  早餐准备好了
Honey, breakfast is ready.
亲爱的
Honey.
再不吃就凉了
It'll get cold.
什么
What?
早上好
Morning.
瞧  亲爱的  这次做得很完美
Look, babe, they're perfect this time.
要是巴里进来怎么办
What if Barry walks in?
要是他看见刚才那幕
What if he could have seen that?
看见
See...
巴里在哪
Where's Barry?
你昨晚没睡好吗
Did you get enough sleep last night?
亲爱的  我知道我们还没抓到蝉
Look, babe, I know that we haven't caught Cicada,
但凯特琳的免疫能力能帮到我们
but Caitlin's immunity can help us.
蝉是谁
Who's Cicada?
我们的头号敌人
Our big bad.
巴里  你还好吗
Barry, are you okay?
我是巴里吗
I'm Barry?
你怎么了
What is wrong?
亲爱的  回答我
Honey, hi. Talk to me.
我昨晚没睡好
I did not get enough sleep.
你确定不是因为我做的早餐吗
Are you--you sure it's not my cooking?
因为
'Cause...
不是  不是
No, no.
闻起来很香
These smell delicious.
谢谢
Thank you.
你知道吗
You know what?
我觉得你打电话给辛格队长
I think that you call Captain Singh
跟他请一天假吧
and you ask for a day off.
你一直做了这么久的英雄
Look, with all the superhero-ing you've been doing,
我认为你值得休息一天  亲爱的
I think you've earned it, honey.
你觉得我应该去尖端科研实验室吗
You think maybe I should go into S.T.A.R. Labs?
怎么
What-- what?
只有我丈夫会觉得研究神速力方程式
Only my husband would think working on Speed Force equations
算是放一天假
would be called a day off.
我爱你  巴里·艾伦
I love you, Barry Allen.
我爱你  爱瑞丝·韦斯特艾伦
I love you, Iris West-Allen.
有人闯入伊沃实验室
Break in at Ivo Labs.
西斯科在通讯器里说的
Cisco's on comms.
尖端科研实验室见
I'll meet you guys at S.T.A.R. Labs.
太快了
Whew. That's a rush.
抱歉  我昨晚擦拭了戒指
Sorry, I polished it last night
落在梳妆台上了
and left it on our dresser.
巴里  你这次干了什么
Oh, Barry, what have you done this time?
巴里  有人闯进伊沃实验室
Barry, we got a break-in at Ivo Labs,
有两个人持枪要偷钻石
two armed men going after diamonds,
就是用来做导体的那些
the ones they use for conductors.
别跑太快
Hey, pump the brakes.
你现在得往回跑
You're gonna have to hang a U-ey,
因为你跑过头了  伊沃在前面18个街口
'cause you passed Ivo by about 18 blocks.
找到了
Found it.
有人对工作很兴奋啊
Someone's excited to get to work.
现在工作太早了
It is too early for this.
想也别想  闪电侠
Forget it, Flash.
我们要带走钻石  不然这个人就要死
We're leaving with the diamonds, or this guy dies.
我说了后退
I said back off.
你在那里干什么
Hey, what are you doing there?
用闪电拳打他啊
Just hit the guy with the lightning punch.
你辜负了这座城市
You have failed this city.
我敢肯定这不是你的台词
Pretty sure that's not your line.
你的肾上腺指数爆表了
Your adrenaline levels are off the charts.
怎么回事
What's going on?
用这么过火吗
Overkill much?
警察要来了
Cops are on the way.
不如让他们接手吧
Why don't you just let them take over from here?
他没事吧  凯特琳
So he's fine, Caitlin?
天哪  感谢上帝
Oh, God, thank goodness.
真的吗  没有异常现象吗
Really? There are no anomalies?
我没有脑肿瘤
I don't-- I don't have a brain tumor?
什么都没有吗
Nothing?
巴里  你的身体非常好
Barry, you're in perfect shape.
宝贝  可不是嘛  看看这些腹肌
Babe, tell me about it. I mean, hi, these abs.
都是我的
And they're all mine.
也许我们不要在公众场合秀恩爱
Maybe we could lay off the public displays of affection,
专心工作吧
just at work, you know?
从什么时候开始
Since when?
你总是说爱抚是你对爱的表达
You're always saying that touch is your love language.
没错  拉尔夫
That's right, Ralph.
只是觉得这样太不在乎你们的感受了
Just feel like we're being very insensitive to all of you.
我们聊过这个话题的
Oh, man, we've talked about this.
我已经不想吉普赛了
I'm over Gypsy, okay?
但是我很感激你这么想
But I appreciate the thought.
我会没事的
I'll be all right.
我要回家
I'm gonna go home...
因为我要好好思考一下
Because I need to think.
思考
Think?
你们在干什么
What are you guys doing?
跟着你到走廊
Following you into the hallway.
因为事情不对劲
'Cause something is definitely up.
你要聊聊吗
You need to talk about it?
是啊  巴里
Yeah, Barry,
你一个上午都不太对劲
you haven't seemed like yourself all morning.
我没事
I'm fine.
我只是想我也许应该
I just think that maybe I should go
去找一个更能理解我现在经历的人
and talk with someone who might better understand
谈一谈
what I'm going through.
我要去见见奥利弗·奎恩
I'm gonna go see Oliver Queen.
去去就回
I'll be back.
星城
狄格  你怎么会在这里
Dig, what are you doing here?
我要把你打得屁滚尿流
I'm kicking your butt.
给我起来  来吧
Now get up, come on.
你们重新装修了地堡吗
You guys redecorate the Bunker?
奥利弗  你可来过天眼会无数次了
Oliver, you've been to ARGUS a million times.
奥利弗
Oliver?
我是奥利弗·奎恩
I'm Oliver Queen.
是  我知道
Yeah, I'll say.
我是绿箭侠
I'm the Green Arrow.
我的天
Holy crap.
[天眼会]
我面对了不少难搞的对手  是吧
I've been hanging with a tough crowd, huh?
那当然  你以为呢
Yeah, you think?
我需要打个电话给尖端科研实验室
Look, I need to make a call, just to S.T.A.R. Labs,
有些重要的绿箭侠的任务要做
just for some important Green Arrow business.
-你知道什么情况  -等下
- You know how it is. - Later.
怎么了
What's that?
布莱特瓦的人和波提纳尔家族在
We've got Bratvas fighting Bertinelli's
老迪亚兹位于贫民区的武器库械斗
over in old Diaz weapons cache in the Glades.
我真的需要些后援  奥利弗
I could really use some backup, Oliver.
天  我不知道我现在行不行
Oh, man, I don't know if I'm feeling up for it.
我想我刚才扭到哪里了
I think I just tweaked something.
天眼会快速反应小组在做另一个任务
ARGUS rapid response is on another mission.
只有我们才能及时赶到
We're the only ones that can make it in time.
-那好吧  我去  -很好
- Okay, yeah, I'm in. - Good.
穿上战衣
Suit up.
我怎么穿这...
How do I put this...
我忘记了  我是不是有人帮我才能穿上
I forget, do--do I need help putting this on?
你在做什么
What are you doing?
我还以为你要先射一发燃烧箭呢
I thought you going to fire an incendiary arrow.
我也是
So did I.
你看到了吗
Did you freaking see that?
别瞎搞了  快去抓司机
Stop fooling around and get the driver.
该死
Damn.
狄格尔
Diggle!
别别
No--no.
天啊  见到你可真好
Oh, man. Oh, I'm glad to see you.
是啊
Uh-huh, yeah.
衣服不错
Nice outfit.
这绝对不可能是巧合
This can't be a coincidence.
这背后肯定是有什么原因
There--there has to be a reason behind this,
也意味着有人在背后作祟
which means that someone is responsible.
我们需要知道...  你能不能别这样
We need to know who--hey, can you--can you not do that?
老天  好一个"诡异星期五"
Man, what a total "Freaky Friday."
等下  咱们没有交换身体
No, wait, we didn't switch bodies.
更像是《时空怪客》的设定  镜子在哪
It's more of a "Quantum Leap." Where's a mirror?
专注一下好吗
Focus, just for a second,
这事很严肃  整个世界认为
and take this seriously because the world thinks
你是奥利弗·奎恩  而我是巴里·艾伦
that you're Oliver Queen and that I'm Barry Allen,
我是非常想知道是为什么
and I would really like to know why.
-完全同意  -可以吗
- Totally. - Is that cool?
-好的  -谢谢你
- Yes. - Thank you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
真怪异
Weird.
市长啊
Hey, Mayor.
你能不能就认真个90秒
Just, if you could--just for 90 seconds of seriousness.
你得承认  这有些酷吧
You gotta admit, this is a little cool.
要是明天早上我在自己床上醒来
I will find it a lot cooler when I wake up
我会觉得比这酷多了
in my own bed tomorrow morning.
你和爱瑞丝在一张床上醒来的
You woke up in bed with Iris?
我们得赶紧想法变回去
We have to fix this right now!
让我理清一下
Let me get this straight.
你认为你不是巴里·艾伦
You believe that you are not Barry Allen,
实际上他才是
but in fact, he is?
巴里  你是不是又穿越时间了
Barry, did you time travel again?
不  我没有
No, I didn't.
-她在和巴里说话  -抱歉
- She's talking to Barry. - Sorry--
我就是巴里
I am Barry.
-对  我还是"疯狗"呢  -冷静  疯狗
- Yeah, and I'm Wild Dog. - Easy, Wild Dog.
那是讽刺
Sarcasm.
讽刺的不怎么样  西斯科
It's not great sarcasm, Cisco.
-你介不介意我  -不  当然不会
- Do you mind if I... - No, of course not.
奥利弗的脑部扫描很正常
Oliver's brain scan is perfectly normal,
没有催眠或是物理干涉的迹象
no signs of hypnosis or psychic interference.
超光速粒子也没有
Tachyon meters are clear.
也没有人乱搞时间线
No one's screwing with the Timeline.
约翰·康斯坦丁
在《明日传奇》S4E07中修改了时间线
别这样  这简直太疯狂了
Guys, come on, this is crazy.
我是说  我绝对不可能
I mean, there's no way that
嫁给奥利弗·奎恩
I could be married to Oliver Queen.
抱歉  但是宝贝
Sorry, but, babe,
你知道他不是我喜欢的类型  对吧
you know he's not my type, right?
爱瑞丝  你真的不相信我吗
Iris, you really don't believe me?
我们说的是真的
We're telling the truth.
好吗  我们说的是真的
Okay? We're telling the truth.
现实发生了很大很大的错误
Something is very, very wrong with reality.
没错
Yeah.
好吧  闪电侠小组开会
All right, Team Flash meeting.
巴里  没你的事
Not you, Barry.
他不是
Th--uh...
我眼里只有你  你知道的
I've only got eyes for you, you know that.
你要是敢碰她
I sw--if you touch her...
我没碰她
I didn't touch her.
那你也想了
You thought about it.
如果你的人不打算帮我们
All right, well, if your team's not gonna help us,
我们得另想办法了
then we have to keep moving.
他们会帮我们的好吗  他们会的
They'll help us, okay? They'll help us.
我们得让爱瑞丝先相信我们
We just gotta get--we just gotta get Iris on board first.
好吧  你打算怎么说服她
Good--fine, how--how are you going to convince her?
不是我去  你去
I'm not, you are.
-他是你的妻子  -我知道  兄弟
- She's your wife. - I know, man.
我和你一样也不喜欢这样
I know, I don't--I don't like this anymore than you do.
你得告诉她你有多么在乎她
You just gotta tell her how much you care about her.
告诉她  她是你的避雷针
Tell her she's your lightning rod.
我才不要那么说
I'm not--I'm not saying that.
就这么说  相信我
Just say it. Trust me.
百试百灵
It works every time.
介意我过来聊聊吗
Mind if I join you?
来吧
Yeah.
喝点大概会好
This should help.
我看你忘了你喝不醉
I guess you forgot you can't get drunk?
这一天不能更糟了
This day could not get any worse.
你真的认为自己是奥利弗吗
You really think that you're Oliver?
当然
Yeah.
奥利弗进监狱的时候费利西蒂给我打过电话
You know, Felicity called me when Oliver was in prison.
你知道他为什么进了斯拉博赛监狱吗
Do you know how he ended up in Slabside?
她给你打过电话吗
She--she called you?
巴里  他跟司法部达成了一个协议
He cut a deal, Barry,
完全是背着费利西蒂的
completely behind Felicity's back.
他甚至都没有提醒她
He didn't even warn her.
联调局突然就出现  把他抓走了
The FBI just showed up and took him away.
这都是她说的吗
She said all that?
她很伤心
She's hurting.
奥利弗的一生都是充斥着
Oliver's life, it's completely defined
愤怒和复仇
by anger, vengeance.
因此有你在我的生命里是多么幸运
That's why I am so lucky to have you in my life.
你就一点也不担心
Are you not the least bit worried
现实已经被破坏了吗
that reality might be broken?
你就不愿意考虑我们告诉你的是事实吗
Don't you have to consider what we're telling you is the truth?
难道没一点可能吗
Isn't it possible?
是的  有可能
Yeah, yeah, it is,
因此我非常抱歉  巴里
which is why I'm really sorry, Barry.
你能不能...  我以为我喝不醉
Would you--I thought I couldn't get drunk.
是雷·帕尔默提供的纳米机器人
Nanites, courtesy of Ray Palmer.
不管你是谁  我们得让你待在安全的地方
Whoever you are, we need to get you to a safe place
直到弄清楚到底发生了什么
until we can figure out what happened.
我希望你能理解
I hope you can understand.
不是吧
Oh, come on.
抱歉了  兄弟
Sorry, dude.
搞什么
Oh, come on.
伙计们
Guys, come--
伙计们  别这样
Guys, come on!
放我们出去
Let us out of here!
拜托
Come on.
我们为什么在你的秘密监狱里
Why are we in your secret prison?
这不是监狱
It's not a prison.
是一个抑制超能力的特斯拉导体管
It's a Tesla conductor tube that dampens meta-powers.
好吧  这里就是个监狱
Okay, it's a prison.
我们只需说服大家
We just need to convince everybody
我们没有疯
that we're not crazy!
如何
How?
你认为我们应该怎么做
How do you suggest that we do that?
因为世界上所有人都认为你我是对方
Because everyone on Earth thinks that we're each other.
-就是这个  -什么
- That's it. - Hmm?
也许只有地球一被影响了
Maybe it's just Earth-1 that's been affected.
如果我们能找到一个外推器
If we can get an extrapolator,
穿越到地球三十八去找到卡拉
breach to Earth-38 and find Kara.
如果她记得我俩  也许她能帮忙
If she remembers us, then maybe she can help
解决现在的问题
fix whatever's happened.
你都没说我们如何逃出去先
You skipped the part where you explain how we escape.
你能跟天眼会联系上吗
Were you able to get in touch with ARGUS?
我尝试过了  但是总是在
Well, I tried, but I kept getting interference
650纳米受到干扰
at 650 nanometers.
那不是红光的波长吗
Isn't that the wavelength for red light?
是红光  没错
Red light, exactly.
我检查城市天气摄像头的时候
And when I checked the city's weather cams,
发现了
this is what I found:
红色天空  黄色闪电
red skies, yellow lightning.
所以你觉得巴里和奥利弗的精神错乱
So you think Barry and Oliver's shared psychosis
是因为怪异的天气
is a result of weird weather?
更怪的事也见过  对吧
Stranger things, right?
行  我再分析一下他们的扫描结果
Okay, I'll run their scans again.
最好现在就放弃
Best off giving up now.
哪个家伙在说话
Who the frak is that?
过去七个月我都被关在顶级安全监狱里
I spent the past seven months in a maximum security prison,
但不管情况有多糟糕  确实很糟糕
and no matter who bad things got--and they got bad--
每个监狱都有马桶
every cell had a toilet.
你确定憋不住了吗
You sure you can't hold it?
你是想让水管堵塞
Oh, you wanna back up the pipes.
没错  然后把阻尼器烧焦
And fry the dampener, yes.
好主意
That's a good idea.
好
Okay.
问题是  我戴着手铐
One problem, I'm not gonna be able to reach the valve
碰不到阀门
with these on.
你要把你的大拇指移位
You're gonna have to dislocate your thumb.
你疯了吗  我...
Are you crazy? I'm--
我没疯  你要把你的大拇指移位
I'm not crazy. You need to dislocate your thumb.
给关节加压就可以
Just apply pressure to the joint.
不行  我会把手弄折的...
No, I'm gonna break my hand--
你不会弄折你的手
You're not gonna break your hand,
因为在这个现实中
because in this reality,
你的韧带被阿纳托利·克尼亚杰夫拉伸过
your ligaments have been stretched and conditioned
已经训练出适用于逃跑的技术了
in the art of escape by Anatoly Knyazev.
好了  勇敢点  给关节加压
Now, man up, apply pressure to the joint,
把你的大拇指移位
and dislocate your thumb.
-成功了  -是的
- It worked. - Yeah.
好了
All right.
行了  现在就等着吧
Okay, now just wait for it.
阻尼器关闭了  现在怎么办
Dampener's down. Now what?
你要带我从这里穿越出去
You're gonna have to phase us out of here.
什么
What?
穿越
Phasing.
就是我用和空气相同的频率震动
That's when I vibrate at the frequency of air,
给我体内的细胞强烈刺激
causing all the cells in my body to get so excited
我就可以穿过坚硬的物质
I can pass through solid objects.
行  "穿越"
Right, "Phasing."
要我给点建议吗
Want any advice?
一秒钟内说完  行吗  巴里
One-second cure. Barry, please.
我就这么一说  穿越不容易
I'm just saying, it's not an easy move,
如果搞砸了
and if you screw this up
你就只有半个身体
then you're gonna come out of the phase
穿过玻璃了
halfway through the glass.
什么
What?
你笑什么
Why are you laughing?
我还没注意到...
I didn't realize...
-你的大拇指太好笑了  -天哪
- Your thumb looks ridiculous. - Oh, my God.
我都不知道我自己的大拇指长这样
I didn't realize that's how mine looked.
瞧吧  你成功了
Well, look at that, you did it.
很好
Great.
别把我丢下  哥们
Don't leave me, man.
我会了
Figured it out.
好了  我们走吧
All right, let's go.
拿上外助推器  然后离开这里
Get the extrapolator and get out of here.
我不能让你这么做  巴里
I can't let you do that, Barry.
爱瑞丝  拜托  我知道这很奇怪
Iris, please, I know how weird this is,
但你心里一定知道  我们说的是实话
but somewhere inside, you know we're telling the truth,
你知道我就是巴里
that it's me, Barry.
你还记得我刚搬到你们家的时候吗
Do you remember when I first moved in?
我妈妈被杀害后  乔带我到你们家
Joe brought me to the house after my mom was killed.
我看着你说  "不是我爸爸做的"
I looked at you and I said, "My dad didn't do it."
-然后你说...  -"我相信你"
- And then you said... - "I believe you."
你总是信我的
You always did.
现在我需要你再相信我一次
And now I need you to believe me again.
爱瑞丝  你是我的避雷针
Iris, you're my lightning rod.
快走  趁我没有改变主意
Quick, before I change my mind.
我们会修复的  我保证
We'll fix this, I promise.
[肯特农场]
堪萨斯州  斯摩维尔
地球三十八
我在写了
I'm writing it.
这事我们已经说好了  宝贝
We've been over this, hon.
没有  是你说了  我没听
No, you talked, I ignored.
你需要新的消声器了
You need a new muffler.
这是个连杆的头吧
I think this is a tie rod end.
快来  卡拉  过来帮我说话
Come on, Kara, back me up here.
还是算了吧
Uh, no, thanks.
不要跟露易丝·莱恩辩论
I know better than to get involved
这个道理我还是懂得
in a debate with Lois Lane.
但是你知道那种感觉
But you do know the feeling,
那种渴望  你脑后那种燃烧的感觉
that itch, that fire in the back of your head,
一定要写成报道的那种诱惑
the siren song of a story that has to be written.
是  我知道
Yeah, I do, I do.
人们肯定想知道为什么露易丝·莱恩
The world is gonna want to know why Lois Lane
和超人一起去了阿尔戈市
went to Argo City with Superman.
要有细节  我会编出原因
Details, I'll make up a reason.
新闻讲述真相的理念也就到这里了
Oh, so much for truth in journalism.
说这话的记者  可是写自己
Says the reporter who writes about
作为超人时壮举的那位
his own exploits as Superman.
我是第一个登上氪星残余部分的人类
I was the first human to set foot on what's left of Krypton,
我看到了宝石山
to lay eyes on the Jewel Mountains,
忍受着高级议会
to endure the endless,
无休止的  折磨人的审议
torturous deliberations of the High Council,
我还得把它写出来
and I have to write about it.
这是露易丝·莱恩的一小步
One small step for Lois Lane,
却是露易丝·莱恩事业的一大步
one giant leap for Lois Lane's career.
这是从一位已经成为两个星球上最著名的
Says the woman who is already the most famous, feared,
让人敬畏的  勇敢的记者口中说出的话
and intrepid reporter on two planets.
但是这座农场上有人
And yet someone on this farm
时薪仍然比我多赚21美分
is still making 21￠ on the dollar more than me.
我指的不是卡拉  亲爱的
And it ain't Kara, honey.
你们两个继续
You two catch up.
我要去使劲砸一些小东西
I am gonna go slam some small things really hard.
爬梯子的时候小心点
Okay, just be careful on that ladder.
它很旧了
It's really old.
你会接住我的
You'll catch me.
休息一下吗  老板
Break time, boss?
我从来没受到过这种质疑
I've never been challenged like that before,
直接被当面问道
just to my face:
"告诉我们你是谁  超女"
"Tell us who you are, Supergirl."
除了格兰特女士
Well, except for Ms. Grant.
我敢相信这威胁
Well, and I'm sure it was harder
由总统做出时会更难面对
when it's the president doing the threatening.
-还是凯特更可怕  -是啊
- Cat was scarier. - Yeah.
你认为我做得对吗
Do you think I did the right thing?
我们的秘密身份会保护我们爱的人
Our secret identities, they protect the people we love
不受到敌人的威胁
from being threatened by our enemies.
没有什么事比这一点更重要
There aren't a lot of things more important than that.
不得不离开超查部我感觉很难过
I'm just sad I have to leave the DEO,
现在剩艾丽克斯一个人  我感觉让她失望了
and now Alex is there alone. I feel like I let her down.
但我也是留你一个人保护地球
Oh, and then I left you to defend Earth alone
好让我可以去阿尔戈
so I could go to Argo.
-不  -我很抱歉
- Nah-- - I'm sorry.
不要为了这件事抱歉  那里是家
No, don't be sorry about that. It's home.
我很高兴你终于能去见它
I'm really glad you got to see it finally,
和它相处
connect with it.
这不仅是与我们的文化产生联系
It was more than just connecting with our culture, you know?
我没事
I'm okay.
还有露易丝
You know, it was Lois.
我在阿尔戈经历的一切新事物
Everything new that I experienced on Argo,
她也在经历
she was experiencing it too.
在那里我们都是陌生的外来访客
You know, out there we were-- we were both strange visitors.
我听起来一定很自私
I must sound so selfish.
不  爱是世界上最无私的东西
No, love is the most unselfish thing in the world...
在任何星球上
On any world.
关于这一点
Well, about that.
有件事我得和你谈谈
There's something that I've needed to talk to you about.
好
Okay.
等一下  等一下
Wait, wait, wait.
-你们是谁  -我们没有恶意
- Who are you? - We come in peace.
露易丝  等等
Lois, wait, wait.
这是巴里和奥利弗  他们是朋友
This is Barry and Oliver. They're friends.
等等
Wait.
所以你知道我是奥利弗  他是巴里
So you know that I'm Oliver and he's Barry?
对  我为什么会不知道
Yeah, w--why wouldn't I?
天啊
Oh, man.
好吧
Okay.
二位  这是我的堂弟克拉克
Um, you guys, this is my cousin Clark.
很高兴你们能见面
I'm so glad you get to meet.
你的堂弟  那个堂弟吗
Your cousin. That cousin?
超人堂弟
The super cousin?
别这样  叫我克拉克
Oh, please, call me Clark.
欢迎来到我们的农场
Uh, welcome to our farm.
真酷
Cool.
你这是在挺胸吗
Are you puffing out your chest?
是
Yes.
露易丝·莱恩  《星球日报》
Lois Lane, "Daily Planet."
等等  你们为什么认为我认不出你们
Wait, why did you guys think I wouldn't recognize you?
因为
Well...
这招倒是挺新的
Oh. Well, that's new.
我们需要你的帮助
We could use your help.
所有小队去韦德和奥古斯丁交口
All units to Waid and Augustyn.
中城 地球一
有东西在破坏伊沃实验室
Something's destroying IVO Labs.
获取超能力者数据
完成
他有我们的超能力
He has our powers.
拜托  兄弟
Okay, come on, man.
我整个下午都在射击油漆罐
I mean, I've been shooting paint cans all afternoon.
除非有一桶油漆可以改写现实
Unless--unless a paint can rewrote reality
-让我们交换生活...  -我知道
- and made us swap lives... - I get it.
那么你需要实战训练  巴里
Then you need actual combat training, Barry.
好吧  知道吗
All right, fine. You know what?
要不你到那边去  跑向我
Why don't you go over there, run at me,
我来试着用箭射中你
and I'll try and hit you with an arrow.
好的
Right, okay.
你把遥控弓箭藏到哪里了
Where did you bury the remote control bows?
哥们
Dude.
拜托  我可不是你
Come on, I'm not you.
好吧  没问题
Yeah, well, okay.
准备
Ready!
来了
Here we go.
不错的尝试
Nice try.
我已经为这等了四年了  兄弟
Oh, I've been waiting four years for that, man.
这是无价的  等等
Oh, it's priceless. Hold on.
需要拍张照片
Need to get a photo.
什么
What?
我搞定了  别担心  再等一下
I got it, don't worry. Hold on a second.
太棒了
That's great.
你觉得这很好笑吗
You think this is funny?
你觉得我的技术是个笑话吗
Do you think my skills are a joke?
得了吧  兄弟
Come on, man.
你射我的时候  我表现得比你好多了
I was a much better sport when you shot me.
我射你是为了教你侦察环境
I shot you to teach you how to case an environment.
你射我是为了嘲笑我
You shot me to get a laugh.
-好吧  -你知道吗
- All right. - You know what?
好了  好了  朝我来
Fine, fine. Come at me.
试着一击命中
Try to get--try to get one hit in.
揍他  巴里
Deck him, Barry!
什么  他是个混蛋
What? He's a jerk.
我不会这么做的  我不是这么训练的
I'm not doing this. This isn't how I train.
你还训练啊  真的吗
Oh, you train? Really?
我以为你的超能力是从天上掉下来的
I thought your powers just dropped out of the sky.
如果你是在试着激怒我
If you're trying to get a rise out of me,
这招并不管用
it's not gonna work.
需要一个剧场后排座吗
Need a peanut gallery?
耳朵里没老婆支招你就什么都做不成吗
Can you not do anything without your wife in your ear?
你是认真的吗
Are you serious, man?
费利西蒂发明的远程指挥
Felicity invented quarterbacking.
我觉得不来点愚蠢的激励演说
I don't think that you can go more than nine hours
你连九小时都撑不过去
without some sappy motivational speech.
我不会这么做的
I'm not doing this.
你的队伍背叛了你
Your team betrayed you.
你需要他们  但他们不在
You needed them, and they weren't there.
我不会这么做的
I'm not doing this.
如果你真的知道该怎么用我的速度
You know, if you really knew how to use my speed,
我绝对动不了你一个指头
I never could have laid a finger on you.
就是这个人在伊沃实验室袭击了我们
That's the guy who attacked us at Ivo Laboratories,
反超能力者适应性动物解剖学有机体
Anti-Meta-human Adaptive Zootomic Organism.
"亚魔卓"
A-m-a-z-o, "Amazo."
有时候这些东西会脱口而出
Sometimes these things just fall into your lap.
上面说天眼会联系了伊沃实验室
It says Ivo Labs was contracted by ARGUS
要求建一个能识别超能力的单位
to build a unit capable of identifying meta-powers.
他不仅仅扫描超能力
He doesn't just scan powers.
他还在泵送"米拉库鲁"血清的纳米自适应混合物
He's pumping a nano-adaptive hybrid of the "Mirakuru" Serum.
所以他就是这样偷走了我们的超能力
So that's how he stole our powers.
他扫描了我们的超能力基因
He scanned our meta-human genes,
然后用米拉库鲁混合物复制了它们
then used the Mirakuru hybrid to copy them.
所以一个邪恶版高仿高特
So an evil copycat Gort
出自《地球停转之日》
要来炸飞世界了
is coming to klaatu barada kick-to our asses,
我们还不能让闪电侠和绿箭侠去应战
and we can't let out Flash and Green Arrow to fight it?
如果他们还在的话我们本来可以的
Well, we could if they were still here.
告诉他们发生了什么  爱瑞丝·韦斯特·艾伦
Why don't you tell them, Iris West-Allen, what happened.
快点
Hurry.
你放他们出去了
You let them out?
好了  听着  我知道你在想什么
Okay, look, I know what you're thinking.
但是我跟奥利弗说话的时候  或者不论他是谁
But I spoke to Oliver, or whoever he is,
我能感觉到什么
and I could feel something.
各位  我觉得我真的在和巴里说话
Guys, I felt like I was really talking to Barry.
我相信你
I believe you.
外面真的很奇怪
It is weird out there.
红色的天空  巴里和奥利弗
These red skies, Barry and Oliver--that,
我在极速实验室看到的那个人
and I vibed somebody in the Speed Lab.
-什么  -没错
- What? - Yeah.
头上有奇怪皱纹
Some guy with ridges on his head,
和络腮胡的的那个家伙
these big muttonchops.
你觉得红色的天空  这个家伙
Do you think that the red skies, this guy,
这些不相干的东西其实是有关联的
these disparate events are somehow connected?
所以巴里和奥利弗被一个
So Barry and Oliver were mind-swapped
有络腮胡的人交换了思维吗
by a guy with muttonchops?
老天  这还没到周二呢
Man, it's not even Tuesday.
周二被认为是一周中最随机的一天
系统警告
是亚魔卓
It's AMAZO.
他刚刚进入了城市范围内
He just entered city limits.
寻找超能力者中
发现目标
别告诉我你是来道歉的
Don't tell me you came to say sorry.
我尽量不说道歉的话
I try to avoid saying that word.
老兄  我理解你
Look, man, I get it.
你只是想用你自己的方法帮忙而已
You were just trying to help in your own Oliver way,
你想要激怒我
trying to get a rise out of me
让我也能像你一样战斗
so I'd fight like you.
不只是这样  巴里
Yeah, it's more than that, Barry.
我已经做了很长时间了
I've been doing this for a very long time.
几乎每次我吃一堑长一智的时候
And nearly every time that I learn a lesson,
伴随而来的是痛苦的回忆
it comes with a painful memory.
看着朋友们死去  我只能杀人才能存活
Watched friends die. I've had to kill to survive.
当我成为绿箭侠的时候
When I'm the Green Arrow,
我能遗忘掉那些痛苦的回忆
I channel those painful memories.
每当我拉开我的弓
I--I draw on a darkness
我都感觉我身处黑暗之中
every time I draw back my bow.
所以看到你  身怀我的能力
So to see you with all of my abilities,
却只在这里嘻嘻哈哈
just laughing and joking around,
我就很生气
it pissed me off,
比我愿意承认的要更气
more than I would care to admit.
当我开始奔跑  感受到我体内的力量
Whenever I run, whatever I'm feeling inside,
悲痛  内疚  我必须将其抛之脑后
grief, guilt, I've gotta just let it go
专注于我为之奋斗的东西
and focus on whatever I'm running toward:
爱瑞丝  朋友们  以及生活中的欢乐
Iris, my friends, all the joy in my life.
当我高兴的时候  我跑得更快了
When I'm happy, I run faster,
就像你之前穿越的那样
just like when you phased earlier.
你之前有过开心的时光
You were having a good time.
不让自己愤怒起来  你的拇指就不能移位
You couldn't dislocate your thumb until you got angry.
如果你要成为绿箭侠
If you're gonna be the Green Arrow
我就成为闪电侠
and I'm gonna be the Flash...
也许我们要开始表现得更像彼此
Maybe we need to start acting more like each other.
终于达成一致了  天啊
Yes, finally, God.
超级听力  抱歉
Super hearing, sorry.
但是我一直坐在里面
But I've been sitting in there
等着你们俩把这个问题解决
waiting for you guys to figure this out
因为我有许多想法
because I have a lot of thoughts, okay?
我应该多一点微笑
I should smile more.
你确实该试试  或许有帮助
Yeah, maybe you should. It might help.
你们得表演这些角色
You guys have to act the parts.
来吧  试试
Come on, try it.
什么
What?
我是绿箭侠
I'm the Green Arrow.
戴着面具
Wear a mask.
听起来像  我不觉得...
Sound like that--I don't--
西斯科
Cisco?
你好超女  巴里
Hey, Supergirl, Barry...
奥利弗
Oliver.
你现在相信我们了吗
You believe us now?
我们都相信了
Yeah, we all do.
抱歉之前把你们关起来
Sorry we locked you up.
但如果你们原谅了我们
But if you feel like forgiving us
就回到地球一吧
and coming back to Earth-1,
家里面有一点小问题
we've got a little bit of a sitch back home,
这算是个请求  看在上帝的份上
like a please, for the love of God,
有个杀人机器人正在破坏我们的城市
there's a killer robot destroying the city
算是小问题
kind of sitch.
我们需要帮助
We could use some help.
-我们去吧  -你跟我们来吗
- Let's do it. - You wanna tag along?
就算你不去  我也会去的  斯摩维尔
If you don't, I will, Smallville.
超人童年所在的小镇
太好了  你是谁
Cool. Who are you?
一位朋友
A friend.
西斯科在哪里
Where the hell is Cisco?
我来了
I'm right here.
而且我把大人物带来了
And I brought the big guns.
他们在干什么
What are they doing?
试着让亚魔卓失去平衡
Trying to keep AMAZO off balance
让它没有时间复制他们的能力
before it has time to replicate their abilities.
解决掉它
Finish him.
没有活动的迹象
No sign of movement.
干得不错
Nice work.
我们很幸运
We got lucky.
各位  你们最好赶快让开
Uh, guys, you might want to get out of the way.
他到底在干什么
What the hell is he doing?
就是我们想避免的
Exactly what we wanted to avoid.
这下不好了
Well, that's not great.
亚魔卓复制了他们的超能力
AMAZO copied all of their powers,
现在在寻找更多的能力
and now it's on the hunt for more.
西斯科  你一定能做些什么来阻止它吧
Cisco, there's got to be something you can do to stop it.
你怎么阻止一个把杀人当早餐的T3000
How do you stop a T-3000 that kills for breakfast?
《终结者：创世纪》电影里的反派机器人
它就是个电脑对吧  关掉它啊
It's a computer, right? So just turn it off.
-真讨厌你讲对的时候  -我是对的
- I hate it when you're right. - Well, I'm right.
咱们走吧
Let's go.
-它能相位移动  -这是那招数的名字吗
- It can phase. - That's what that's called?
我们不能打败我们击不中的东西
Well, we can't fight what we can't hit.
我有个主意
I've got an idea.
把他带回到这里
Bring him back here.
没问题
No problem.
快
Move.
当他回来时  把他撂倒
When he comes back, knock him down.
他不能相位移动和奔跑同时进行
He won't be able to phase and run at the same time.
各位  怎么样了
Guys, where are we at?
我觉得我们做到了
I think we got it.
我们对亚魔卓的操作系统进行了反向编程
We reverse-engineered AMAZO's operating system
做了个病毒来抹掉中央处理器
and whipped up a virus to wipe the CPU.
-也没多么难  -除了...
- Not so difficult. - Except...
除了它是个复制了
Except it's a robot that has replicated
他们超能力的机器人
their super strengths, and, thus,
因此现在它无法穿透
now it is impenetrable,
所以你不能在它里面加入病毒
so you cannot put the virus inside it.
这可不妙
That's not great.
好吧  那我们怎么办
Okay, so what do we do?
如果亚魔卓继承了他们的能力
Look, if AMAZO inherited all of their strengths,
那它可能也继承了他们的缺点
then maybe it inherited their weaknesses too.
只是我们不削弱它  爱瑞丝
Only we're not gonna weaken it, Iris.
我们直接送它下地狱
We're gonna send it straight to hell.
奥利弗  超女和超人抓住亚魔卓时
Oliver, you're gonna have to counteract AMAZO's phasing
你要消解它的相位移动
while Supergirl and Superman hold it.
-明白  -我只有一次机会
- Got it. - I'll only have one shot.
现在把那个病毒给我  西斯科
Now, bring me that virus, Cisco.
来这里
Come here.
准备好
Get ready.
好了
Done.
别失手
Don't miss.
我不会的
I won't.
快
Hurry up!
亚魔卓  你辜负了这座城市
AMAZO, you have failed this city.
亚魔卓系统 下线
亚魔卓已被拆解
AMAZO has been dismantled
每个组件都锁在尖端科研实验室的地库
and every piece locked up in a S.T.A.R. Labs vault
除了这个  这是我的纪念品
except for this one. This is my souvenir.
掌声  各位
A round of applause, everybody.
祝贺你  闪电侠
Felicitations, Flash.
你刚刚可真棒
That's quite a performance you did out there.
谢谢  但我依然是奥利弗·奎恩
Well, I appreciate that, but still Oliver Queen.
我依然是巴里·艾伦
And I am still Barry Allen.
我不知道  各位
I don't know, guys.
你一下子就灭了亚魔卓
You took down AMAZO in one shot.
只有绿箭侠可以做到
Only the Green Arrow can do that.
奥利弗你跑过了亚魔卓  就像闪电侠
And, Oliver, you outran AMAZO, just like the Flash.
或许我们应该保持这样
Maybe we should stick with this whole body swap thing
身体交换
for a while.
看起来一切都挺顺利的
Seems to be working okay.
如果你们不换回来
I don't know that anybody would be too worried
我不知道有谁会担心
if you two don't switch back.
不不不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no.
我们得找出是谁这么对巴里和奥利弗
We need to figure out who did this to Barry and Oliver
以及为什么  然后我们得换回来
and why and then we're gonna reverse it, okay?
凯特琳  有什么想法吗
Caitlin, any thoughts?
我还没想清楚
I haven't quite figured it out yet,
但在那之前  我相信
but until I do, I am confident
中城和星城都会安然无恙
that Central City and Star City are in good hands.
说到安然无恙
Speaking of "In good hands,"
我得回去大都会和露易丝身边
I should probably get back to Metropolis and Lois.
如果有什么发生
If anything were to happen,
她的整个世界都会陷入危险
her entire world's unprotected.
好的  我明白
Yeah, yeah, I get it.
谢谢你的帮助  克拉克
Thank you for helping us, Clark.
没有你我们无法阻止亚魔卓
We couldn't have stopped AMAZO without you.
这我可不敢肯定
Oh, not so sure about that.
你好  克拉克
Hello, uh, Clark.
帮我个忙  可以吗
Help a genius out, would you?
我想给你这张支票...
Look, I want to give you this check...
我是义务帮助全人类的
I do this for free, the whole helping humanity thing.
你以为我是要给...
Oh, you think that I'm giving...
不  不是的
no, no, not for that.
这是给我第三任妻子的赡养费
This is a alimony check for my third wife.
她也在地球三十八
She also live on Earth-38,
而且我给的可能有些晚
and I might be a little bit behind in the payment.
能不能帮我个忙...
If you could just do me the favor...
你要我把这个带给你前妻吗
You want me to deliver this to your ex-wife?
前妻  第三任
To my ex-wife, my third ex-wife.
不用谢
You're welcome.
你也不客气
You're welcome too.
太棒了
It's super.
天  我可以相信他的吧
Man, I can trust him, right?
你还好吗
Are you okay?
不好
No.
你成功打败了亚魔卓
You did a great job with AMAZO,
可是代价呢  巴里
but at what cost, Barry?
什么意思
What do you mean?
知道我为什么让你和奥利弗离开吗
Do you know why I let you and Oliver go?
因为我感觉到了
It was because of something that I felt.
当我闭上双眼
When I stopped looking with my eyes
用心去倾听
and I started listening with my heart,
我意识到
I realized that you,
你  巴里·艾伦  一直都是
Barry Allen, have always been
并且永远都会是我爱的人
and will always be the man that I love.
无论我带着哪一张面具
No matter what mask I wear,
都会让你看到最真实的我
I'll always show you my true face.
你要答应我  巴里
I need you to promise me something, Barry.
答应我找到幕后真凶
Promise me that when we figure out who did this to you
夺回神速力
and when you get your speed back
可以回到我的怀抱时...
and you're finally back in my arms...
你一定要回到我身边
That'll you'll come back to me.
我当然会回到你身边
Of course I'll come back.
巴里  我听到你在行动前说的话了
Barry, I heard what you said right before you took that shot.
你现在是绿箭侠了
You're the Green Arrow now.
但请不要变成奥利弗·奎恩
But please don't become Oliver Queen.
我不会的
I won't.
我保证
I promise.
巴里  过来一下
Barry, we need you in the workshop.
你觉得你看到的这个人
So you think this person you saw has something to do
可能与巴里和奥利弗互换的事有关
with what's happened to Barry and Oliver?
他俩互换之后
I mean, I saw him right after
我就看到他了
these two swapped capes.
你最近震波不是经常出问题吗
You've been having trouble with your vibes lately, right?
-会不会是  -不
- Maybe it's that? - No.
这超出了我的能力范围
This was beyond me.
而且似乎很重要
It felt like something important.
让我们看看
We need to see it.
来吧
Okay, hang on.
天啊  我看到了一切
My God, I can see everything.
有意思
Fascinating.
没想到这个地球的人
I wouldn't have thought the men of this Earth
也会有这种能力
had this capacity.
不过没用的
But it won't avail you.
没有人可以阻挡既定的未来
None of you can stop what's been set into motion.
你们最好赶快投降
You're best off giving up now,
因为无论你们做什么
because nothing you can do can alter
都会是徒劳
what's about to happen.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
一点都不
No, not even close.
你们看到了什么
What did you see?
这个
This.
我不认识他
I don't recognize him.
没关系
Doesn't matter.
我知道去哪里找他
I know where to find him.
我们接下来怎么办
So what's our next move?
我们去哥谭市
We go to Gotham city.